#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/dayaorn (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Telemetry

Education

**ANCC Certification Review** 

#### Certifications

Certified Professional in Healthcare Quality (CPHQ)

Nurse Executive Advanced, Board Certified (NEA-BC)

Critical Care Certification (CCRN-K)
Basic Cardiac Life Support (BCLS)

#### Honors-Awards

2017 Becker's Hospital Review Rising Stars: 60 Healthcare Leaders Under 40

2006 Ten Outstanding Students of the Philippines

#### **Publications**

SUCCINCT: A Prior to Report Nursing Huddles

The Role of Ambulation in the Development of Deep Venous Thrombosis, A Review of Literature

SUCCINCT: A Prior to Report Nursing Huddles

Breaking the Fall: Decreasing Falls Through A Nurse-Led Fall Collaborative Review

Hitting the 99th Percentile: How Medication Information Cards Helped in Raising Patient Awareness and Satisfaction Among Patients in Medical, Surgical, and Telemetry Areas

# Jerome Mendóza Dayao

CNO and Senior Associate Administrator at UW Medicine Harborview Medical Center

Seattle, Washington

# Summary

Doctorally prepared, board-certified (NEA-BC, CPHQ, CCRN-K,) c-level, healthcare senior executive in a large tertiary academic and public hospital; designated level 1 adult & pediatric trauma center, and regional burn referral center for the states of Washington, Montana, Idaho, & Alaska.

Elected in 2019 to serve a three-year term as a member of the Board of Directors for the American Organization for Nursing Leadership (AONL formerly AONE) representing region 9 (California, Nevada, Hawaii, Oregon, and Washington)

Elected Board Member, Region 9
American Organization for Nursing Leadership (AONL) - California,
Washington, Oregon, Nevada, Arizona, and Hawaii

Board Member, Regional Policy Board, Region 9 American Hospital Association (AHA)

At-Large Board Member
Northwest Organization of Nurse Leaders (NWONL)

Board Member, Healthcare Advisory University of Washington School of Nursing and Health Studies Bothell, Washington

Named as one of the 2017 Becker's Hospital Review Rising Stars: 60 Healthcare Leaders Under 40.

Servant Leader promoting excellence in Human Caring through kindness & gratitude.

# Experience

UW Medicine
CNO and Senior Associate Administrator, UW Medicine Harborview
Medical Center
July 2019 - Present (1 year 1 month)

Seattle, Washington

Reporting to the hospital chief executive officer (CEO), responsible and accountable for executive leadership and oversight of all professional nursing practice and patient care services at Harborview Medical Center: the only designated Level I adult and pediatric trauma for Washington, Alaska, Montana, & Idaho. HMC also serves as the regional trauma and burn referral center for the WAMI region, and the disaster preparedness and control hospital for Seattle and King County.

UW Medicine is one of the top-rated academic medical systems in the world. With a mission to improve the health of the public, UW Medicine educates the next generation of physicians and scientists, leads one of the world's largest and most comprehensive medical research programs, and provides outstanding care to patients from across the globe. UW Medicine's four hospitals—Harborview Medical Center, Northwest Hospital & Medical Center, University of Washington Medical Center and Valley Medical Center—admit more than 64,000 patients each year. A network of hospital-based and outpatient clinics, including 12 UW Neighborhood Clinics, see more than 1.3 million patients each year.

The UW School of Medicine, part of the UW Medicine system, leads the internationally recognized, community-based WWAMI Program, serving the states of Washington, Wyoming, Alaska, Montana and Idaho. The UW School of Medicine has been ranked No. 1 in the nation in primary-care training for more than 20 years by U.S. News & World Report. School of Medicine faculty receive more than \$1 billion per year in research funding, ranking it as the top public institution recipient of biomedical research funding from the National Institutes of Health (NIH) and second among all public and private institutions for NIH funding.

Arrowhead Regional Medical Center 6 years CNO 2017 - July 2019 (2 years) Colton, California Reporting to the hospital executive director (CEO), responsible and accountable for executive leadership and oversight of all professional nursing practice in a large and busy (>100,000 ED visits) trauma and teaching public hospital. Oversees over 2,000 employees across 38 cost centers.

Arrowhead Regional Medical Center (ARMC) is a 456-bed teaching hospital. The hospital, located on a 70-acre campus in Colton, California, operates a regional burn center, a primary stroke center, a level II trauma center, a behavioral health center located on the hospital campus, four primary care centers including three family health centers, and provides more than 40 outpatient specialty care services.

Associate CNO & Assistant Hospital Administrator 2013 - 2017 (4 years)
Colton, California

UCLA Health Resource RN 2011 - 2016 (5 years) Los Angeles, California

Cedars-Sinai RN I to IV 2008 - 2013 (5 years) Los Angeles, California

Long Beach Memorial Medical Center RN I to II 2007 - 2011 (4 years) Long Beach, California

## Education

University of California, Los Angeles

Doctoral Degree in Nursing Practice, Health Systems Leadership (2020)

University of Pennsylvania - The Wharton School Executive Education | Nursing Leaders Program (2015)

California State University-Los Angeles

Master of Science Degree, Nursing Administration - 3.8 GPA · (2014)

Page 3 of 4

Wesleyan University

Bachelor of Science in Nursing (BSN) 4.0 GPA - Magna Cum Laude · (2006)